AKSHAT SHAH

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

🖄 axat17@gmail.com 🕲 akshatshah.dev 🔌 +1 (908) 842-3844 👂 Roseland, NJ 📮 https://www.linkedin.com/in/axat17/

SUMMARY

Senior Software Engineer at ADP, Full Stack Developer with 5+ Years of Experience, Front End React JS Specialist, and with Skills like HTML5, PostCSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Apollo GraphQL, Stencil, Splunk, MongoDB, AWS, Azure, and Express JS

EMPLOYMENT

ADP LLC

Senior Software Engineer · Feb. 2018 to Current · Roseland, NJ, USA

- Work on a Project where ADP wanted to retire old Console based application with React Based Single Page application.
- Created a new GraphQL server from scratch and migrate old Express JS microservices.
- Maximum Utilization of Splunk to maintain logs and make more interactive dashboards using Splunk queries to provide more helpful insight into each feature of the product.
- Working on Next-Generation Micro front End Solutions to Break existing monolith Front End Application into Dynamic reusable solution.
- Utilized libraries like Stencil, JavaScript Dynamic Import, GraphQL, Apollo and Cypress for to achieve a long-term solution.
- Working with DevOps for Automated Deployments and Testing. Using technologies like, Jest, React JS, Node JS, MongoDB, Jenkins, Express, GraphQL, PostCSS, and TypeScript.

Kaltech Consulting Inc

MEAN Stack Developer, Contractor (Client: Prudential Financial) · Oct. 2017 to Feb. 2018 · Roseland, NJ, USA

- Migrate Old C# based windows application to responsive single page web application using technologies like Angular 4.0, Express JS, MongoDB, and SiteMinder.
- The application was built around W3C Standards. Use Python script to move SQL Based database to MongoDB a Document based database.
- Brand new APIs were developed using Express JS and converted them into microservices to make application performance faster.
- SiteMinder was used to provide SSO features for in house users.
- Use Splunk to log the API request details to make sure debugging is faster and help us collect the technical statistics.

Silicon Tech Solution

Development Intern · Feb. 2017 to Sept. 2017 · Fremont, CA, USA

- Used C# to build RESTful Microservice with the use of OOPS and Data Structure to deliver only needed data to UI.
- Angular 1.6 was used to developed Responsive User Interface with Google material design.
- Frameworks like Jasmine and Selenium were used to build test suits for the project.
- MongoDB was used to make sure that database performance stays as faster as possible.
- Tools like GIT, Jenkins, Jura, and Docker were used to collaborate with other teammates and keep the application up and running.

MentorPower Software

Web Developer · June 2014 to Aug. 2015 · Ahmedabad, GUJ, India

- Convert old .Net Windows-based application to new Web Based Application using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, and C# for APIs.
- Use a framework like Selenium and Jasmine for testing and Jenkins and for deployment.
- Work with other developers to document code and set good standards during the development.

EDUCATION

Campbellsville University · Jan. 2018 to Aug. 2019 Master's Information Technology Management 2019

Northwestern Polytechnic University · Sept. 2015 to Dec. 2016 Master's Computer Science 2016

Ganpat University · Jan. 2011 to May 2014 Bachelor's Information Technology 2014

SKILLS

React JS, Node JS, GraphQL, Angular JS, Express JS, Stencil, TailwindCSS, Splunk, PostCSS, TypeScript, Object-Oriented Programming, C#, .NET, RESTful, MongoDB, SQL, PLSQL, Jasmine, Jest, Karma, Selenium, Python, Docker, Jenkins, SiteMinder, Azure, AWS, Agile, Jira, Rally, BitBucket, GIT